The infinite expanse of space...
The universe is filled with silent light...
Some stars cease to exist, while other stars come to life.
That’s right.
The universe is alive...
...alive...
...alive !
That is why it needs love.
I feel empty...
...so empty.
What was the meaning of all those lives ?
In the course of human life, is there anything so valuable that deserves such pain ?
What we need is love...
...a tremendous love that can root out all the pain.
Don’t you think so...
...Teresa ?
Everything is predetermined,
but there’s much more to it.
To the soldiers of a distant planet...
You too, as well as everything else.
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Earth Defense Force Special Joint Fleet
All ships have warped out.
Fleet, form a deep battle formation.
Garmillas Force Frontier Guard 38th Task Force
All ships, prepare for anti-ship combat.
Begin data link.
Radar operators, pay attention
to the grid display change.
Earth-Garmillas Joint Fleet
It’s been 60 days since they
seized the Floating Continent.
Garmillas has given up on
rescuing their base's crew.
Our targets are the Gatlantis fleet
and the 8th Floating Continent base.
The glory of recapturing the Floating
Continent is expected of us, the Earth Fleet.
The Garmillas force will charge as a spearhead while we destroy the left-overs individually.
Armored assault Zoellugut Class...
Long ships are rare among the
Garmillas fleet, and we’ve got three !
Collect every bit of data you can on it.
The chance of watching its
durability this close is like...
Aihara !
Garmillas is our ally.
Show some respect to your allied ships.
Yes, Captain Kodai !
Begin data link with the Zoellugut class ships.
Gatlantis fleet has launched hostile units from multiple bases of the 8th Floating Continent...
...forming a defense line ahead of our line of attack.
Report from our alert observation unit.
Beware of special types with firepower transfer...
Joint fleet has reached the mission area.
Roger. Continue monitoring
the development of our mission.
Vanguard unit at the front of our
formation is about to engage in combat.
Earth fleet, advance.
Our fleet has begun attacking.
Significant damage to our forces !
The Gatlantis main fleet is advancing !
That ship...?!
ID confirmed.
It’s the Yunagi, ship No. 47
of the 2nd Escort Destroyer Fleet.
Fighters launching from that carrier !
Fire the top side missiles !
Four torpedoes from tubes 1 through 4 !
Attack angle, 3 degrees !
Fire !
The enemy fleet appears to be backing off !
They're pulling back to the Floating Continent !
Backing off ?!
The timing of their withdrawal is unusual.
The Garmillas fleet is pursuing them.
Open a direct channel to the Garmillas flagship.
Aye, sir.
A huge unidentified object has
emerged behind the Gatlantis fleet.
What ?!
W...what the hell is that ?
Is that...
A super battleship.
The lead Garmillas fleet has been annihilated !
Units 6 and 7, annihilated !
Pull back immediately.
Chief, this situation may be our chance.
Ensure none of our ships are in the line of fire.
That’s an absolute requirement.
Yes, sir.
Inform all ships in the field to initiate Plan A !
All ships, execute the plan immediately !
Plan A ?
What's that ?
I don’t know.
But it’s pre-set into the fleet network...
That’s...
...impossible.
Twenty-four...
...twenty-three...
...twenty-two...
...twenty-one...
...twenty...
...nineteen...
...eighteen...
...seventeen...
Pull back immediately to the 3rd alert line.
That’s the directive of Plan A.
Never heard of it.
...ten...
...nine...
...eight...
...seven...
...six...
...five...
...four...
...three...
...two...
...one...
...zero.
Extra-dimensional implosion detected !
W...wave motion gun ?!
From where ?!
Please promise me...
Please promise me that you will never repeat our folly.
I promise.
Kodai, face reality.
Earth was seriously damaged in the previous war.
In order to survive...
This is Earth Federation Defense Force Flagship Andromeda.
Earth Federation Defense Force Andromeda Class
Ship No.1 - Andromeda
Destruction of the 8th Floating Continent is confirmed.
Proceeding to the sweep up operation.
Earth-Garmillas joint fleet, await further orders.
You have my respect
for your brave fight thus far.
This is...
We were just a sideshow !
The Andromeda...
So it's already been completed.
The Andromeda has entered the battle space.
It’s a success.
Dispersion wave motion gun...
The citizens of Garmillas will change their minds.
So will the protesters on the Earth side.
Enemy ship detected.
Is it dead ?
Defiance and Saratoga are incapable
of continuing the mission due to damage.
They're requesting permission to perform
a long-range warp to the Earth sector.
Permission granted.
Wave motion gun...
That was a wave motion gun, wasn’t it ?
Is this Earth’s answer to the past three years ?
Re-ignition of the enemy ship’s propulsion detected.
Main guns, prepare to fire !
It’s accelerating rapidly.
Forget the front guns, No. 3 and 4, fire !
Fire !
Enemy Gatlantis ship,
approaching at breakneck speed !
What ? Take evasive action !
Are you sure ?
Yes, the Saratoga and the Defiance warped to Earth just before the enemy ship did !
Emergency warp !
We’re heading to Earth !
A large mass has warped out
in the outer rim of the Moon's orbit !
What ?
Saratoga and Defiance’s warp-out signatures were confirmed in the same spot, so...
...the large mass must be the Gatlantis
ship which warped from the battle space !
Status of the combat satellites ?
They've just begun auto interception.
It broke through the combat satellites !
Gatlantis ship has passed the Moon !
It’ll enter the atmosphere in 400 seconds !
Where’s the expected point of impact ?
Here !
Wha...
This is how Gatlantis fights.
Mr. Serizawa, I’m sorry, but this is an emergency !
Please issue an evacuation order
to the entire capital immediately !
It's no use. Once something with that much mass traveling at that speed crashes...
I’m starting the evacuation program for civilians.
Open the passageways to the old underground cities.
A warp-out signature near the enemy ship.
K-47, it’s the Yunagi !
Kodai !
Enemy ship directly above !
It’s on an atmospheric entry course !
Prepare to fire main guns ! Fire !
No good !
Yunagi’s main guns are just...
Cease fire.
Course correction !
Come around below the enemy ship !
We'll push the enemy ship from below
to change its course ! Maximum thrust !
T...the Yunagi has made
contact with the enemy ship.
Kodai...
It's no use !
The entry trajectory hasn’t changed !
Captain, Lieutenant Mori of HQ
is hailing on the confidential line !
From Yuki ?
Connecting !
Kodai, listen. I’m switching lines.
Kodai.
Sanada...?!
Send me the trajectory data.
Can you really do that in
such a short period of time ?!
Evacuation of the 3rd block has begun.
Open the 7th block.
Moving the pallets.
We’re pulling out. Prepare for reverse thrust.
Roger.
We'll put our hopes in that ship.
All personnel in the dock area, escape to
the ship or the evacuation block immediately.
I repeat.
All personnel in the dock area, escape to
the ship or the evacuation block immediately.
Hey, hurry !
This way !
Get inside now !
Activation
Auxiliary engine, check complete.
Energy charge, 100%.
Circuit, nominal. Auto-cylinder, ready.
Start the auxiliary engine.
Starting the auxiliary engine.
Heavy power line, contact.
All energy switches on.
Prepare for artillery and projectile combat.
Astro-nav rotation, 1600.
Auxiliary engine, ignition.
Releasing the gantry locks.
Raise the hull.
Firing angle correction, 35 degrees.
Fire !
W...we're safe.
R...report !
Y...y...yes, sir.
Enemy ship was destroyed
at an altitude of 18,000 meters.
They got it ?
Sanada...
It’s the Yamato !
The Yamato seems to have taken the shot !
What ? It’s supposed to
be undergoing modification.
Patch me through to the under-sea dock immediately !
Yamato...
What ? What’s going on ?
Captain Okita !
Kodai, get on board the Yamato.
Get on board the Yamato.
Episode 01
AD 2202 - Resurrection of the Space Battleship Yamato
Sono hito no yasashisa ga hana ni masaru nara
If that person's gentleness exceeds that of the flowers
Kodai Susumu:
Mori Yuki:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Tokugawa Hikozaemon:
Emoto Isami:
Kiryu Mikage:
Yamazaki Susumu:
Okita Juzo
Todou Heikuro:
Serizawa Kotetsu:
Yamanami Hajime:
Zorder:
Starsia:
Teresa:
Operator A:
Operator B:
Operator C:
Operator D:
Radar Officer:
Observer:
Ono Daisuke
Kuwashima Houko
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Mugihito
Tsuda Kenjiro
Nakamura Eriko
Tsuchida Dai
Sugao Takayuki
Kojima Toshihiko
Genda Tessho
Ebara Masashi
Tezuka Hideaki
Inoue Kikuko
Kanda Sayaka
Ryumon Mutsuki
Sugai Kazuho
Fujinuma Kento
Karasuda Hiroshi
Kikumoto Taira
Matsumoto Sinobu
Sono hito no utsukushisa ga hoshi ni masaru nara
If that person's beauty exceeds that of the stars
Kimi wa te wo hirogete mamoru ga ii
You had better open your arms and offer protection
Karada wo nagedasu neuchi ga aru
It's worth risking your life
Hitori hitori ga omou koto wa ai suru hito no tame dake de ii
Each of you had better think about the person you love
Kimi ni hanasu koto ga aru toshitara ima wa sore dake kamo shirenai
If there's anything I can say, perhaps that's all for now
Ima wa saraba to iwasenai de kure
Don't make me say goodbye for now
Don't make me say goodbye for now.
Preview
We've been called upon...
We should go.
You're not alone any more.
Kodai, I’m already happy.
Meet Ambassador Barrel.
You’ll know the true identity of the vision.
We must go forward.
Tense Infiltration into the Embassy on the Moon
Episode 02